[The Blessed Bride] [Episode 21]
[العروس المباركة] [الحلقة 21]
Why did you steal the antidote for her?
لماذا سرقت الترياق لها؟
I never expected that it would be you.
لم أتوقع أبدًا أنه سيكون أنت.
So what if I'd stolen it?
فماذا لو سرقتها؟
Although I like Ye,
على الرغم من أنني معجب بك ،
she's someone who Ye likes too.
إنها شخص تحبه أيضًا.
Of course I would help her.
بالطبع سوف أساعدها.
I didn't know that though Your Highness is usually arrogant,
لم أكن أعلم أنه على الرغم من أن صاحب السمو عادة ما يكون متعجرفًا ،
you are pretty kind.
انت لطيف جدا.
It's none of your business!
هذا ليس من شأنك!
I save whoever I want to save.
أنقذ كل من أريد أن أنقذه.
Unlike you,
على خلافك،
a despicable man who only uses poison.
رجل حقير لا يستخدم إلا السم.
You're already
أنت بالفعل
not the honorable princess now.
ليست الأميرة الشريفة الآن.
You are my prisoner!
أنت سجيني!
Let me ask you.
دعني أسألك.
Did you feed her the antidote?
هل أطعمتها الترياق؟
Of course I did.
بالطبع فعلت.
You can't get it back now
لا يمكنك استعادتها الآن
even if you want!
حتى لو كنت تريد!
(Did she really feed me the antidote?)
(هل أطعمتني حقًا الترياق؟)
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
Your Highness
صاحب السمو
shall take this poison on behalf of her.
يأخذ هذا السم نيابة عنها.
Stop it!
توقف عن ذلك!
Zhou Han.
تشو هان.
Long time no see, my sister.
لم أرك منذ وقت طويل يا أختي.
I almost forgot about you.
كدت أنسيتك.
Come at me.
تعال عندي.
Release her.
أطلق سراحها.
You can't even save yourself.
لا يمكنك حتى إنقاذ نفسك.
How dare you ask me to release her?
كيف تجرؤ أن تطلب مني إطلاق سراحها؟
Because I know
لأنني أعرف
you're a person who likes to negotiate.
أنت شخص يحب التفاوض.
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
Feel free to tell me.
لا تتردد في إخباري.
You're indeed my good sister.
أنت حقا أختي الطيبة.
You understand me right away.
أنت تفهمني على الفور.
I do need your help with one thing.
أنا أحتاج مساعدتك بشيء واحد.
If you retrieve a treasure map for me from Ling's Residence,
إذا استعدت خريطة كنز لي من Ling's Residence ،
I'll let both of you go
سأترك كلاكما يذهبان
and detoxify Her Highness.
وإزالة السموم صاحبة السمو.
Did I ask you to save me?
هل طلبت منك أن تنقذني؟
I don't need your help.
لست بحاجة لمساعدتكم.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
I shall show my sincerity first.
سأُظهر إخلاصي أولاً.
Today,
اليوم،
I'll let both of you go first.
سأترك كلاكما يرحل أولاً.
Her Highness is dying.
سموها تحتضر.
Whether to save her life or keep the treasure map,
سواء لإنقاذ حياتها أو الاحتفاظ بخريطة الكنز ،
you should know what to do.
يجب أن تعرف ماذا تفعل.
Let's go!
لنذهب!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Are you alright?
هل انت بخير؟
Your Highness! Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!  صاحب السمو!
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
I am sorry.
أنا آسف.
I dragged you into this.
لقد جرتك إلى هذا.
Ling Qiye.
لينغ تشي.
Her Highness stole the antidote for me,
صاحبة السمو سرقت الترياق لي
so Zhou Han got angry
لذلك غضب تشو هان
and fed her poison.
وأطعمت سمها.
My poison is cured now.
شفي سمي الآن.
As for Her Highness' poison...
أما سم سموها ...
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll get the antidote for her.
سأحضر الترياق لها.
♪The old vines grow outside the window♪
الكروم القديمة تنمو خارج النافذة
♪I can't help but sigh in the middle of the night♪
♪ لا يسعني إلا أن أتنهد في منتصف الليل ♪
♪I walk through the bustling streets outside the west of town♪
أمشي في الشوارع الصاخبة خارج غرب المدينة ♪
I am sorry.
أنا آسف.
♪Magpies chirp and I quietly watch the sunset♪
♪ تغرد طائر العقعق وأنا أشاهد غروب الشمس بهدوء ♪
Didn't the physician say
ألم يقل الطبيب
there's a way to relieve the symptoms?
هل هناك طريقة لتخفيف الأعراض؟
Did you forget about the Yangchun Pills?
هل نسيت حبوب يانغتشون؟
♪It reminds me of every scene of her♪
يذكرني بكل مشهد لها
I thought
اعتقدت
you forgave me
لقد سامحتني
when you fed me the medicine.
عندما أطعمتني الدواء.
You haven't even given me an explanation till now.
أنت لم تقدم لي حتى تفسيرا حتى الآن.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Since you wanted to leave,
منذ أن أردت المغادرة ،
♪Dance with the sword while you are young♪
♪ ارقص مع السيف وأنت صغير
leave then.
فلترحل إذا.
♪Who's willing to write a new song for you?♪
♪ من يرغب في كتابة أغنية جديدة لك؟
♪Whether it's fate or yearning, everything's a dream♪
♪ سواء كان القدر أو التوق ، كل شيء حلم ♪
Are you satisfied now?
هل أنت راض الآن؟
Ye.
انتم.
Don't be angry.
لا تغضب.
Aren't we doing this
ألا نفعل هذا
for the sake of Madam Ying?
من أجل سيدتي يينغ؟
Moreover, look!
علاوة على ذلك ، انظر!
Isn't Madam Ying getting better now?
ألا تتحسن سيدتي ينغ الآن؟
I really feel sorry for Madam Ying.
أشعر حقا بالأسف على سيدتي يينغ.
She's severely poisoned at such a young age.
لقد أصيبت بتسمم شديد في مثل هذه السن المبكرة.
And she needs
وهي بحاجة
to take the antidote once every month.
لأخذ الترياق مرة كل شهر.
We don't even know when will the poison take effect next month.
نحن لا نعرف حتى متى سيصبح السم ساري المفعول الشهر المقبل.
Will it
فإنه سوف
happen after our wedding?
يحدث بعد زفافنا؟
I will confirm the wedding date as soon as possible.
سأؤكد موعد الزفاف في أقرب وقت ممكن.
Alright then.
حسنا اذا.
The production of this poison is complex and tedious.
إنتاج هذا السم معقد ومضجر.
And
و
so is the antidote.
وكذلك الترياق.
If you add one wrong herb,
إذا قمت بإضافة عشب واحد خاطئ ،
the antidote will become poison.
سيصبح الترياق سمًا.
It's so scary!
إنه مخيف جدا!
Your behavior now
سلوكك الآن
is scary too.
مخيف جدا.
Ye.
انتم.
I did lie to you.
لقد كذبت عليك
But it's because I love you.
لكن هذا لأنني أحبك.
I'm willing to do anything for you.
أنا على استعداد لفعل أي شيء من أجلك.
But what did Yue Liuying
ولكن ماذا فعل يو ليويينغ
do for you?
أعمله من أجلك؟
She's only
هي فقط
an assassin sent by Zhou Han.
قاتل أرسله تشو هان.
She's a liar!
إنها كاذبة!
[Adapted from the comic "My Dear Concubine" drawn by Ah Weiwei and Muxi Huanhuan]
[مقتبس من الفيلم الكوميدي "My Dear Concubine" الذي رسمه Ah Weiwei و Muxi Huanhuan]
♪Looking pretty in the wedding gown, I'm forced to get married♪
♪ أبدو جميلة في ثوب الزفاف ، أجبرت على الزواج ♪
♪Within these high walls, can I escape after having met you?♪
♪ داخل هذه الأسوار العالية هل أستطيع الهروب بعد أن التقيت بك؟ ♪
♪Late at night, I can't fall asleep with so much sadness♪
♪ في وقت متأخر من الليل ، لا أستطيع النوم مع الكثير من الحزن
♪Despite the many restrictions, I live a carefree life♪
على الرغم من القيود العديدة ، أعيش حياة خالية من الهموم
♪Turns out my mood will be much better with you around♪
♪ تبين أن مزاجي سيكون أفضل بكثير معك حولك
♪Seeing your smile, I will not run away from here again♪
برؤية ابتسامتك لن أهرب من هنا مرة أخرى
♪Enjoying the sunset in the bamboo forest, your face crosses my mind♪
استمتع بغروب الشمس في غابة الخيزران ، وجهك يخطر ببالي ♪
♪I'm falling for you gradually although I say otherwise♪
♪ أنا أقع في حبك تدريجياً رغم أنني أقول غير ذلك ♪
♪I'd like to say♪
♪ أود أن أقول ♪
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
♪Looking pretty in the wedding gown, I'm forced to get married♪
♪ أبدو جميلة في ثوب الزفاف ، أجبرت على الزواج ♪
♪Within these high walls, can I escape after having met you?♪
♪ داخل هذه الأسوار العالية هل أستطيع الهروب بعد أن التقيت بك؟ ♪
♪Late at night, I can't fall asleep with so much sadness♪
♪ في وقت متأخر من الليل ، لا أستطيع النوم مع الكثير من الحزن
♪Despite the many restrictions, I live a carefree life♪
على الرغم من القيود العديدة ، أعيش حياة خالية من الهموم
♪Turns out my mood will be much better with you around♪
♪ تبين أن مزاجي سيكون أفضل بكثير معك حولك
♪Seeing your smile, I will not run away from here again♪
برؤية ابتسامتك لن أهرب من هنا مرة أخرى
♪Enjoying the sunset in the bamboo forest, your face crosses my mind♪
استمتع بغروب الشمس في غابة الخيزران ، وجهك يخطر ببالي ♪
♪I'm falling for you gradually although I say otherwise♪
♪ أنا أقع في حبك تدريجياً رغم أنني أقول غير ذلك ♪
♪I'd like to say♪
♪ أود أن أقول ♪
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
[The Blessed Bride]
[العروس المباركة]
[Adapted from "My Dear Concubine" on Cloud Comic]
[مقتبس من "My Dear Concubine" on Cloud Comic]